repoweramerica.org 2017-08-07

# Privacy Policy - Climate Reality Action Fund

_Last updated Oct. 27, 2016._

The Climate Reality Action Fund (“Action Fund,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) is very sensitive to online privacy concerns. This online privacy policy describes how we treat all user data, whether collected online or offline, including data collected during your visits to the Action Fund’s mobile apps, social media pages and other branded digital properties (each, a “Website”). 

By accessing and using our Website or providing us information by any other means, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Action Fund’s privacy practices, including with regard to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information. If you do not agree to any of the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should discontinue use of this Website immediately and/or refrain from providing us information by any other means. 

#### Collection of Personally Identifiable Information 

On the Website, you can access more information about our goals and programs, download materials, make donations, and enjoy other interactive services. The Action Fund maintains an e-mail list to keep interested parties informed about its various activities. Individuals can unsubscribe from the e-mail list at any time. 

The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected on these pages include: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card number, and information about your preferences. Personal information does not include “aggregate” information, which is data we collect about the use of the site or about a group or category of services or users, from which individual identities or other personal information has been removed. 

You may also submit personal information to us offline, for example, when you request information, sign a petition, or make a donation. We treat your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, whether it is collected online or offline. 

You may request to review, update, correct or delete the personal information that we have collected about you by sending your request to [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org) or to: 750 9th Street, NW, Suite 520, Washington, DC 20001. Please note that if you request the deletion of your personal information, we may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or to enforce our rights. 

####  Privacy of Our E-mail List and Personal Information

The Action Fund maintains an e-mail list to keep interested parties informed about its programs. Individuals can unsubscribe from the e-mail list at any time. We collect and use your personal information to operate the Website and to deliver any services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content based upon the information we have collected (for example, special information for users living in a particular region or state). 

Only Action Fund staff and our authorized agents have access to personally identifiable information provided by visitors to this Website in order to better serve you. People who affirmatively submit their contact information through this Website may be contacted by Action Fund staff or authorized agents. 

We do not share the information you’ve given us with unaffiliated groups without your explicit permission. We may share some of your personal information with the following affiliated groups: 

  * Affiliated Third Parties — for example, licensed affiliates or affiliated campaigns that share our mission and privacy concerns.
  * Third-Party Service Providers – For example, our database administrators (for the sole purpose of helping us do our work), credit card processing services, and vendors and organizations we engage to help us provide services or facilitate large distributions of messages. 

By using the Website and otherwise submitting your information to us, you authorize us to contact you as described above. If you wish to unsubscribe from an e-mail list, you can let us know by following the "unsubscribe" instructions that are included in each promotional email. To opt out of other communications, please send your request to [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org) or mail to: 750 9th Street NW, Suite 520, Washington, DC 20001. Please note that such requests may take up to ten (10) days to become effective, and you may not opt out of receiving communications regarding your transactions with the Website or technical information about the Website and services. 

Personal information collected by the Action Fund may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities, which may include countries that do not require the same level of protection for personal information as the one in which you reside. For example, if you use the Website to submit information directed to one of our licensed affiliates that is located outside of the United States, your information will be transmitted to the country in which the licensed affiliate is located. By using the Website, you expressly consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. 

We also may share the personal information you’ve given us as follows: 

  * to respond to your requests for customer service or other information or services 
  * to comply with applicable laws, cooperate with law enforcement, government requests, subpoenas, court orders or legal process
  * to enforce our Terms of Use 
  * to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  * to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required or permitted by law
  * in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or disposition of all or any portion of our business or operations (including without limitation in connection with bankruptcy or any similar proceedings)
  * certain information provided in connection with petitions and surveys (see below).

####  Petitions and Surveys

For petitions and surveys you’ve signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information – for example, we may provide compilations of petitions, with your comments, to the intended recipient of the petition or survey. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit it to the intended recipient of the petition or survey as part of the petition or survey. This is standard industry practice in such situations. In no such case will we disclose your e-mail address or phone number, without your permission. We may also make your comments, along with your first name, city and state available to the press and public online. 

####  Notice of Privacy Rights of California Residents

We have adopted a policy of not sharing your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes if you request that we do not do so ("Opt-Out Policy"). You may make such a request by sending us an email at [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org). When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, e-mail address, and what personal information you do not want us to share with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Please note that there is no charge for controlling the sharing of your personal information or for processing this request. 

If you are a California resident and have provided personal information to a business without an Opt-Out Policy, you may be entitled by law to request certain information regarding disclosures of personal information made by such business to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year ("Disclosure Request"). Such business is not required to respond to more than one Disclosure Request per customer each year, or to respond to requests made by means other than through the contact information designated by the business for such purposes. However, please note that due to our Opt-Out Policy described in the preceding paragraph, we are not obligated by law to provide you with the information in your Disclosure Request. 

To make a Disclosure Request, please contact us at [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org). In the Disclosure Request, specify that you seek your “California Customer Choice Privacy Notice.” Please allow thirty (30) days for a response, but note that we are entitled by law to respond to your Disclosure Request by notifying you of your right to prevent the disclosure of personal information pursuant to our Opt-Out Policy, which is cost free to you. 

####  Collection and Use of Children’s Personal Information

We do not solicit personally identifying information from children. Visitors who are under 13 years of age should ask their parent or legal guardian for permission and assistance if using the Website and should not submit any personal information to the Website. 

If you do provide information to us, you represent and warrant that you are 13 years of age or older. 

If you are 13 – 17 years of age, you may visit, browse and use the information on the Website, and if you submit any personal information, you represent and warrant that your parent or guardian (i) has given permission for you to use the Website and (ii) agrees to this Privacy Policy on your behalf. If you are a parent or guardian and believe we may have inadvertently collected personal information from your child under 18 years of age, please notify us immediately by sending an e-mail to [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org). 

####  Use of Cookies & Other Technologies

We may use cookies to tailor your experience on this Website according to the preferences you have specified. When you visit the Website, your browser may save a tiny piece of information on your computer, mobile phone or other device. This information personalizes and improves your experience online. It is not possible and we do not attempt to access information from other websites. Our cookies do not contain any personal identifiable information. 

You have the ability to accept, decline and delete cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you chose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience all features of our Website. 

We may also use tracking technologies, such as web beacons, pixels, gifs, tags and other technologies that collect information to personalize your experience, facilitate your browsing on the Website and improve the quality of the Website. We may also use these technologies in e-mails (for example, to track open rates for our mailings). This practice helps us determine which web pages and mailings appeal most to our users. We may use the information collected through pixel tags, tracking links and similar technology in combination with your personal information. 

####  IP Addresses, Log Files, and Data Analysis 

As with any website operator, we analyze our Website logs to constantly improve the value of our Website. We use an external service to provide real-time reporting to us and our authorized agents of browser accesses to our Website. This includes page views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods. We do not use this service to gather, request, record, require, collect, or track any Internet users’ personally identifiable information. 

We log IP addresses which describe the location of your computer or network on the Internet. This information is helpful for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We may also use third-party services such as Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google. These practices help us understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our Website. We may also use embedded images in e-mails to track open rates for our mailings. This practice helps us determine which mailings appeal most to our members. 

URLs contained in e-mails may contain an ID that enables us to correctly identify the person who takes an action using a web page. We use URLs to simplify the process of signing petitions and filling out surveys. We may occasionally present a shortened URL that references a longer URL which contains an ID. We do this to simplify the display, to prevent links from becoming broken when copied, and to ensure compatibility with e-mail programs which do not handle long URLs. When shortened URL is displayed in an e-mail, you will see the full URL in the browser’s address bar when you access the page. 

####  Protection of Personal Information 

The Action Fund uses industry standard, reasonable and technically feasible physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help protect personal information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure. However, the Website and data storage are run on software, hardware and networks that may experience security breaches that are beyond our control, and no transmission of data over the internet is guaranteed to be completely secure. We are not responsible for the acts or omissions of any third parties, and we cannot guarantee the security of the information on and sent over the internet. Any such transmission is done at your own risk. 

####  Third Party Links 

We may include links to third-party sites on our Website or forms or in our communications. We try to link only to reputable organizations, but because these other sites are not hosted or controlled by us we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites or the content provided thereon. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those sites. 

####  Governing Law 

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the internal substantive laws of the District of Columbia without respect to its conflict of laws principles. Those who choose to access the Website from locations outside of the United States are responsible for compliance with local laws if and to the extent local laws are applicable, including without limitation, all applicable laws, rules and regulations regarding the transmission of data exported from the United States or the country in which you reside. The Action Fund may limit the Website’s availability, in whole or in part, to any person, geographic area or jurisdiction, at any time in its sole discretion. 

####  Changes to This Policy 

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy, especially as new features are added to this Website. If there are material changes to this statement or in how we will use your personal information, we will prominently note such changes prior to their implementation. Any changes in the Privacy Policy will take effect upon posting and apply only to information collected from you on and after the Last Revised Date, unless we have other communications with you. 

We encourage you to periodically check for updates to the Privacy Policy and to review the policy to be informed of how we are collecting, using, disclosing and protecting your information. We also encourage you to review our Terms of Use at <http://climaterealityactionfund.org/terms.php> to be informed of the terms and conditions applicable to your use of our Website. 

Contact If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact the Climate Reality Action Fund at: [info@climaterealityactionfund.org](mailto:info@climaterealityactionfund.org).
